<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stage4 | Сайтик</title>
    <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/ru/category/stage4/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://anpolienko.github.io/ru/category/stage4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Stage4</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>ru</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://anpolienko.github.io/en/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Stage4</title>
      <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/ru/category/stage4/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Presentation</title>
      <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/ru/post/presentation-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anpolienko.github.io/ru/post/presentation-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A presentation goes beyond the idea of crafting a catchy document to present in front of an audience. It is an art in which a person relies on communication skills to introduce a topic relevant to a group of people, regardless of its size. Different elements participate in this communication process, such as body language, presentation skills, visual tools, etc. and are key in delivering an effective presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we shall present a detailed guide on how to make a presentation, intended both for newcomers in this subject but also for professional presenters who seek to improve the performance of their presentations. Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-presentation-and-what-is-a-powerpoint-presentation&#34;&gt;What is a presentation, and what is a PowerPoint presentation?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is essential to highlight the difference between Presentation and PowerPoint Presentation, often interchangeable terms. &lt;strong&gt;One thing is a presentation, an audiovisual form of communication to present information. A PowerPoint presentation is a subset of a presentation.&lt;/strong&gt; Since PowerPoint remains the leading tool in the market for creating presentations, the term was coined by both spectators and presenters. Let’s begin by checking the main differences between the two terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-a-presentation&#34;&gt;What is a presentation?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A presentation is any situation in which a person or group has to transmit a message in front of an audience. The format by which the audience attends can answer the following categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live crowd:&lt;/strong&gt; A presentation in which the average number of spectators exceeds 100 people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massive event:&lt;/strong&gt; Similar to the format above, but we speak about thousands of spectators. This format has specific requirements regarding scenario setup and logistics, and the usual presenters are influencers in worldwide conferences or corporate events (like All-Hands meetings).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private event:&lt;/strong&gt; A selected number of attendants can listen to the presenter. Coaching sessions are the leading kind of private event for presenters, but multiple other categories can fit into this format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online event:&lt;/strong&gt; Following the trends of remote working and what the pandemic has left us in terms of digital immersion, multiple events shifted their large attendance numbers in favor of online settings. This has the advantage of a narrowed setting, as the area in which the presenter has to stand is considerably reduced – with simpler A/V inputs. Attendees are given a link to the event and watch from their computers or mobile devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offline event:&lt;/strong&gt; This medium is what we consume via YouTube videos. Behind each and every YouTube video is countless hours of content development, editing, rehearsing a presentation, and so forth. We call it offline because attendees can browse the content at any time, replaying as desired, unlike Online Events in which the attendees must be logged in to a specific platform. No interaction with the presenter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybrid event:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a format coined by large tech companies, the automobile industry, and even fashion brands. The idea is to create an event where a selected number of attendees are allowed to participate (using the Private Event model). Still, at the same time, the event is streamed for users worldwide (Online Event) and/or available on the official social media networks of the brand (Offline Event).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each one of these formats exposed above has specific requirements in terms of interaction with the audience. For example, in-company presentations will differ from common presentations that seek to capture the interest of new consumers. It is vital to establish the presentation’s intent from the very first moment and then narrow it down according to the topic to present, as well as the knowledge level of your target audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A presentation does not require a slide deck. It is a tool presenters use to make the content more interesting for the audience and also memorable. However, it is well-known that influencer speakers such as Tony Robbins or Warren Buffet ignore PPT documents altogether, preferring to articulate their narrative on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-a-powerpoint-presentation&#34;&gt;What is a PowerPoint presentation?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, a PowerPoint presentation is a specific type of presentation, which involves the usage of a slide deck crafted with PowerPoint. This kind of tool allows presenters to communicate a message through a vast range of mediums, such as images, graphs &amp;amp; charts, audio, and video for a better impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a PowerPoint presentation is an easy process, and there are two routes for it: working from a blank slide or using PowerPoint templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the advantages of building a PowerPoint presentation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better information retention by the audience, thanks to visual cues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves the audience’s focus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to create powerful graphics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templates are editable, meaning you can repurpose the original designs to meet your standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saves time to create presentations thanks to its user-friendly UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourages teaching and learning processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-importance-of-a-good-powerpoint-presentation&#34;&gt;The Importance of a good PowerPoint presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some elements that presenters must take into account when creating a PowerPoint presentation. It’s not just drag-and-drop, then magic happens. Creating a PowerPoint presentation involves a process of generating the graphic content to display and the narrative around it. The purpose of PowerPoint is to serve as a tool to enhance communication, not to make it overly complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We emphasize the relevance of working the speech and graphic content together since the speech itself gives the timeframes for each slide, what elements it contains, or whether it is relevant to use a slide or not to speak about a topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some points to highlight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presenters often use the element of surprise. This means a presentation can start without a slide, use a video, or involve a discussion between two parties, then jump to the slide deck presentation. More on this topic later on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good PowerPoint presentation can be your introduction card in multiple professional settings. The effort you put in terms of design and content shall pay back over time in contacts or business deals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a spare copy of your presentation, preferably in Google Slides presentation format, is a safe-proof technique in case the PPT file gets corrupted. The aesthetic remains the same and can be browsed by any computer with internet access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Week New Recipe</title>
      <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/ru/post/third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anpolienko.github.io/ru/post/third-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week-3&#34;&gt;My week. 3.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When life gives you mint leaves, what do you make? This mint mojito recipe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INGREDIENTS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you’ll need to make this mint mojito recipe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fresh mint&lt;/strong&gt; – The star of this classic cocktail! You’ll muddle some mint leaves to infuse the drink with flavor and add more to your glass for garnish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White rum&lt;/strong&gt; – Jack and I are fans of 10 Cane and Bacardi Silver Rum, but any white rum would work here. Feel free to use your favorite!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fresh lime juice&lt;/strong&gt; – It adds bright, tart flavor. Always, always use freshly squeezed lime juice in this mojito recipe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple syrup&lt;/strong&gt; – Classic mojito recipes call for sugar, but I like to use simple syrup in its place. It streamlines the recipe, as you don’t need to muddle the sugar with the lime and mint. Simple syrup keeps for several weeks in the fridge, so I like to keep it on hand for anytime I’m in the mood for a fun drink.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Club soda or sparkling water&lt;/strong&gt; – It balances the tart lime and alcohol and gives the cocktail a fun fizz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ice&lt;/strong&gt; – You can’t make a cool, refreshing mojito without it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STEPS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to learn how to make a mojito? Here’s what you need to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, muddle the mint.&lt;/strong&gt; Place it in the bottom of a cocktail shaker and use a cocktail muddler to press it until it becomes aromatic. When you’re muddling the mint, your goal isn’t to pulverize it or crush it. Instead, just bruise it slightly to help it release its fragrant oils. This should only take a few taps with your muddler!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, shake!&lt;/strong&gt; Add the rum, lime juice, simple syrup, and a handful of ice to the cocktail shaker, and shake it vigorously until the ingredients are completely combined and chilled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then, strain your mojito.&lt;/strong&gt; Strain the contents of the cocktail shaker over a glass filled with ice. Top your glass with soda water, and garnish it with lime slices and more fresh mint sprigs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, taste and adjust.&lt;/strong&gt; This step is essential anytime you’re making a cocktail at home. It gives you a chance to customize your drink to your tastes, finding a balance of flavors you really love. If you prefer a tarter mojito, add an extra squeeze of lime juice. If you want it sweeter, stir in a bit more simple syrup. Not strong enough? Well, you know what to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
