<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal | Website</title>
    <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/tag/personal/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://anpolienko.github.io/tag/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Personal</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://anpolienko.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Personal</title>
      <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/tag/personal/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell Recipes for Drinks</title>
      <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/post/fourth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anpolienko.github.io/post/fourth-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week-3&#34;&gt;My week. 3.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to learn How to Make Bubble Tea? Here you’ll find everything you need to know to make creamy, delicious, and surprisingly simple bubble tea right at home using simple ingredients like black tea, tapioca pearls, and sugar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With shops selling this hip and trendy iced beverage on practically every street corner these days, I thought it would be fun to share everything I know about Bubble Tea with you guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re new to bubble tea, or you drink it all the time, in this post you’ll find everything you need to know to make simple delicious homemade bubble milk tea at home. I love this version best because it isn’t too sweet, the ingredients are super basic, and it’s ready super fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-bubble-tea&#34;&gt;What is Bubble Tea?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bubble tea is a Taiwanese tea-based beverage that goes by the names &lt;em&gt;milk tea, pearl tea, tapioca tea, boba tea, boba nai cha, foam milk tea&lt;/em&gt;, and several others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invented in the 1980s, the exact story of who invented Bubble Tea is somewhat debated, however, it is believed that Ms. Lin Hsiu Hui of the Chun Shui Tang Tea Shop in Taichung, Taiwan, came up with the drink when she randomly poured fen yuan into her iced tea during a meeting in 1988.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward three decades and this discovery of milk tea mixed with tapioca balls have evolved into hundreds of different unique bubble tea flavor combinations. Bubble tea shops are seemingly everywhere these days (I know of at least three within two miles of my house) and the color varieties, thanks to all the different flavors (like green tea, strawberry, taro, and mango!) seem to keep getting cooler and cooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-boba&#34;&gt;What is Boba?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often synonymous with bubble tea, Boba is actually the little black balls that sink to the bottom of your bubble tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boba pearls are made from partially cooked tapioca flour – the refined starch extracted from the cassava root. Boba is gluten-free and, in its natural state, flavorless. Loved for its chewy texture, Boba can be added to both hot and cold drinks including hot teas or smoothies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INGREDIENTS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you’ll need to make this mint mojito recipe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tea&lt;/strong&gt; – I used a simple English Breakfast Black Tea. High in caffeine (how I like it), it’s what I had on hand and it worked perfectly. Oolong tea would also work nicely, or any other robust black tea. Don’t worry about over-steeping your tea since you will be adding milk (or cream) and some sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Milk&lt;/strong&gt; – I like to use whole milk or half-and-half. Heavy cream is too heavy and low-fat milk doesn’t quite add enough creaminess. Dairy milk and creamer, or full-fat coconut milk are my top picks, but other plant-based milk alternatives (soy milk, almond milk, oat milk) will work, too. For an extra creamy treat, try adding sweetened condensed milk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sweetener&lt;/strong&gt; – The benefit of making bubble tea at home is that you can add as much or as little sugar as you like. The total amount will vary depending on the type of milk you use, how long you steep your tea, and personal preference. In this recipe, I used granulated white sugar, but simple syrup, honey, or agave would also work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ice&lt;/strong&gt; – Of course, these days bubble tea may come either hot or cold. However, in this case, you’ll need ice. Depending on how cool your tea gets will determine how much ice you’ll need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tapioca Pearls (or boba)&lt;/strong&gt; –  This is the boba that I used to make this bubble tea recipe. It is the fast-cooking kind, which means that they don’t take over an hour to cook. In fact, they take just 5-10 minutes. There is one very important thing to note about quick-cooking tapioca pearls – do not make them ahead of time. After just 1-2 hours they will start to stiffen and dry out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STEPS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to learn how to make a mojito? Here’s what you need to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steep the tea:&lt;/strong&gt; Bring approximately 6 cups of water just to a boil and remove from heat. Stir in the sugar and add the tea bags(for this recipe, I added approximately 1 tablespoon of sugar per glass of bubble tea). Allow the tea to steep and come to room temperature. If you’re in a hurry, you may either prepare the black tea ahead of time or transfer the steeping tea to the refrigerator to speed up the cooling process. Allow the tea to steep for at least 15-25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prepare the boba (tapioca pearls):&lt;/strong&gt; Approximately 15 minutes before you plan to serve your bubble tea, bring a small pot of water to a boil. Add the boba and stir well to prevent them from clumping and sticking together. Allow the boba to cook for approximately 5-7 minutes (they should be floating on the surface and super chewy). Drain and rinse under cold water – don’t worry, they won’t fall apart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assemble&lt;/strong&gt; Grab four glasses (any glass will work, just make sure they’re large enough to hold approximately 2 cups of liquid) and divide the cooked pearls between them. Fill each glass with ice and pour approximately 1 to 1 1/2 cups of room temperature black tea into each. Add approximately 2-3 (or more) tablespoons of milk or half-and-half to each glass and stir well to combine. Is it sweet enough? Add additional sweetener if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Week New Recipe</title>
      <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/post/third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anpolienko.github.io/post/third-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week-3&#34;&gt;My week. 3.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When life gives you mint leaves, what do you make? This mint mojito recipe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INGREDIENTS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you’ll need to make this mint mojito recipe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fresh mint&lt;/strong&gt; – The star of this classic cocktail! You’ll muddle some mint leaves to infuse the drink with flavor and add more to your glass for garnish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White rum&lt;/strong&gt; – Jack and I are fans of 10 Cane and Bacardi Silver Rum, but any white rum would work here. Feel free to use your favorite!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fresh lime juice&lt;/strong&gt; – It adds bright, tart flavor. Always, always use freshly squeezed lime juice in this mojito recipe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple syrup&lt;/strong&gt; – Classic mojito recipes call for sugar, but I like to use simple syrup in its place. It streamlines the recipe, as you don’t need to muddle the sugar with the lime and mint. Simple syrup keeps for several weeks in the fridge, so I like to keep it on hand for anytime I’m in the mood for a fun drink.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Club soda or sparkling water&lt;/strong&gt; – It balances the tart lime and alcohol and gives the cocktail a fun fizz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ice&lt;/strong&gt; – You can’t make a cool, refreshing mojito without it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STEPS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to learn how to make a mojito? Here’s what you need to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, muddle the mint.&lt;/strong&gt; Place it in the bottom of a cocktail shaker and use a cocktail muddler to press it until it becomes aromatic. When you’re muddling the mint, your goal isn’t to pulverize it or crush it. Instead, just bruise it slightly to help it release its fragrant oils. This should only take a few taps with your muddler!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, shake!&lt;/strong&gt; Add the rum, lime juice, simple syrup, and a handful of ice to the cocktail shaker, and shake it vigorously until the ingredients are completely combined and chilled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then, strain your mojito.&lt;/strong&gt; Strain the contents of the cocktail shaker over a glass filled with ice. Top your glass with soda water, and garnish it with lime slices and more fresh mint sprigs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, taste and adjust.&lt;/strong&gt; This step is essential anytime you’re making a cocktail at home. It gives you a chance to customize your drink to your tastes, finding a balance of flavors you really love. If you prefer a tarter mojito, add an extra squeeze of lime juice. If you want it sweeter, stir in a bit more simple syrup. Not strong enough? Well, you know what to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s continue our journey</title>
      <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/post/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anpolienko.github.io/post/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week-2&#34;&gt;My week. 2.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October continues. Today let&amp;rsquo;s talk about my favotite coctail - Gin &amp;amp; Tonic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gin &amp;amp; Tonic. If you can say it, you can make it. Right? Right. But also, not exactly. The two-ingredient cocktail requires your undivided attention. From glassware to garnish to style of gin and spirit proof, everything should be carefully considered when mixing a G&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Gin &amp;amp; Tonic made with a potent base—45% ABV and above, if you mean business—and configured with two parts tonic to one part gin is a highball of balance and beauty. Too much gin, and the botanical spirit will overshadow the unique qualities of the tonic. Too much tonic, and it will drown the gin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is endless room for experimentation within those two ingredients. With hundreds of gins on the market and dozens of tonics, a good G&amp;amp;T is a mix-and-match exercise to find the combination that best suits your tastes. London dry gins are characterized by their juniper-forward flavor profile; modern-style gins often dial down the juniper and ramp up the citrus and florals. Some tonics are dry and straightforward, with prominent notes of bitter quinine. Others are sweet and syrupy. And in between, you’ll find tonics featuring everything from citrus and aromatics to herbs and spice. Then, of course, there’s the garnish. Many people swear by a lime. Others choose a lemon, and still others prefer a grapefruit slice or rosemary sprig, or a seasonal garnish such as blood orange and thyme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All those permutations results in a bevy of Gin &amp;amp; Tonics, so naturally, the drink lends itself to creativity. Muddled cucumbers or fruit provide an extra dose of refreshment, and a measure of dry vermouth softens the cocktail. Liqueurs, fresh herbs and even barrel-aged gin are all fair game when you’re making G&amp;amp;Ts. It’s an impressive résumé for a drink that traces its roots to quinine powder, which was used in the 1840s as an antimalarial for British soldiers and citizens in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, the bitter quinine powder was mixed with soda and sugar to make it more palatable. It wasn’t long before enterprising sorts bottled the elixir for commercial use. And soon after that, tonic made its way into gin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, tonic features less quinine than past products, and it has a sweeter taste. But its ability to complement gin is unparalleled among mixers. Put the two together in a glass, and you can taste one of the cocktail canon’s best pairings and raise your glass to the knowledge that Gin &amp;amp; Tonics are, essentially, medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INGREDIENTS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 ounces gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 ounces tonic water (you can use 4 ounces for stronger flavour)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garnish: 2 lime wheels or other seasonal garnishes you may prefer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STEPS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill a highball glass with ice, then add the gin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top with the tonic water and gently stir.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garnish with lime wheels or seasonal garnishes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, world</title>
      <link>https://anpolienko.github.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anpolienko.github.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week-1&#34;&gt;My week. 1.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October started. You can see how i designed my bullet journal for this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s a mulled wine recipe to help you survive autumn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MULLED WINE INGREDIENTS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin, gather your ingredients. For this mulled wine recipe, you will need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wine: No need to splurge on a pricey bottle — a mid-range bottle of dry red or white wine will do. (Or if you’re making a big batch, this is a great recipe to break out a nicer boxed wine too!) The best wine for mulled wine will be fruity and full-bodied, so that it can withstand the heat and not have its flavor completely drowned out by the aromatics. I recommend looking for a bottle of Zinfandel, Merlot, Grenache,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brandy: Similar to sangria, it’s also traditional to spike your mulled wine with an extra bit of liqueur. Brandy is the traditional choice, but Cointreau (or another orange liqueur) or tawny port are also delicious alternatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fresh oranges: One of which we will slice and mull in the wine, one of which you can slice and use as a garnish if you’d like. (Edit: To minimize bitterness, I recommend peeling the orange before simmering it in the wine.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon: I love the making mulled wine with cinnamon sticks, but you could whisk in some ground cinnamon if that’s what you have on hand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mulling spices: These vary in mulled wine from country to country, but whole cloves and star anise are my favorites, plus perhaps a few cardamom pods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweetener: Feel free to add your favorite sweetener to taste. Sugar is classic, but I prefer to naturally sweeten mine with either maple syrup or honey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOW TO MAKE MULLED WINE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make mulled wine, simply…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine ingredients. Combine all ingredients in a saucepan and give them a quick stir.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simmer. Heat until the wine almost reaches a simmer over medium-high heat. (Avoid letting it bubble in any way. Alcohol begins to vaporize at 172°F, so take care to ensure that the wine does not evaporate.)  Reduce heat to low, cover completely, and let the wine simmer for at least 15 minutes or up to 3 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strain and season. Using a fine mesh strainer, remove and discard the orange slices, cloves, cinnamon sticks, star anise and ginger. Give the mulled wine a taste, and stir in your desired amount of extra sweetener if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve. Serve warm in heatproof mugs, topped with your favorite garnishes.
Full ingredient amounts/instructions listed in the recipe below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POSSIBLE VARIATIONS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to customize this mulled wine a bit? Feel free to…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use white wine: This recipe is also delicious (and lovely) when made with a dry white wine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a chai tea bag: In place of the cloves and star anise, feel free to steep 1 or 2 chai tea bags in the mulled wine (preferably caffeine-free, if you are serving this to a group in the evening).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add different aromatics: Feel free to add in whatever aromatics sound fun! Fresh ginger slices, cardamom pods, nutmeg, allspice or lemon zest are some other great aromatics to try.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add garnishes: For a festive touch, feel free to sprinkle some fresh cranberries in the pot a few minutes before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make Crock Pot mulled wine: You are also welcome to try making mulled wine in the slow cooker with the setting on low. I just want to clearly caution that slow cookers can run the gamut when it comes to what they consider a “low” temperature. So if you use a slow cooker, be sure to keep a very close eye on it to ensure that the wine is not accidentally overheated and simmering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
